# KERRY KOVACIK

Austin, TX 78744

Phone: 512-230-4598 | Email: kerrykovacik@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/kerrykovacik/ | Portfolio: https://kerrykova.github.io/

GitHub: https://github.com/Kerrykova

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Data analyst experienced in Excel, VBA, Python and SQL with a background in the financial industry. Self-starter driven to dive down the rabbit hole to investigate and solve mysteries and inconsistencies in data and workflows. Well versed in generating reports and findings to executives and stakeholders. Brings a love of learning, coupled with high attention to detail. Plays an integral part of current cross-functional team, applying these skills to research complex and intricate projects, promote collaboration and manage to completion.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

Databases: mySQL, SQLite, MongoDB

Data Manipulation & Visualization: Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, D3, Tableau

Languages: VBA, Python, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, R

Other: G Suite, Microsoft Office, Extract, Transform, Load (ETL), Flask, SQLAlchemy, Heroku

## **PROJECTS**

NY Citi Bike Program - <a href="https://github.com/Kerrykova/NY-Citi-Bike-Analytics">https://github.com/Kerrykova/NY-Citi-Bike-Analytics</a>

Built a Tableau Story for NYC Citi Bike Data (September 2018 - February 2019).

SQL - https://github.com/Kerrykova/SQL

Wrote a series of gueries and joins on the Sakila sample database.

#### Austin Animal Center Outcomes and City Satisfaction Data -

https://github.com/Kerrykova/AAC-Outcomes-and-City-Satisfaction

• Explored Austin Animal Center outcomes and park and safety satisfaction survey data to build a visualization dashboard. Collaborated with team members to perform ETL from CSV files into a SQLite database and used Flask, JavaScript, Python and Tableau to create the dashboard.

## **E**XPERIENCE

Analyst - Investments, 2013 - Present

Merrill Lynch – Austin, TX

Trade investment accounts with over \$400 million in assets under management. Create and analyze reports and visualizations for 401(k) cost-benefit analysis, commissions tracking, business expenses and reimbursements, and assets under management, etc. Collaborate and manage vendors and clients as 401(k) plan liaison.

- Achieved internal Top 100 in Excellence award 5 years running.
- Build reports and workflows for trading of managed portfolios which has led to a reduction in trade errors.
- Diagnose, research and correct data discrepancies and inaccuracies in internal and external systems, tools and reporting resulting in thousands of dollars in financial savings for our clients.

## KERRY KOVACIK

## Page Two of Two

Executive Assistant / Office Manager, 2006 - 2013

Robert J. Eckhardt & Co., P.C. – Melville, NY

Managed all interoffice operations and processes, such as coordinating multiple teams for tax filing deadlines to ensure no late or missed client submissions to the Internal Revenue Service (IRS).

- Completed individual, sales and payroll taxes as well as W2 and 1099 forms.
- Coded and input expenses to generate financial statements.
- · Calculated internal rates of return and assets allocations for financial portfolios.

## **EDUCATION**

The Data Analysis & Visualization Boot Camp
The University of Texas at Austin – Austin, TX

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in Excel, VBA, Python, R, JavaScript, SQL Databases, Tableau, Big Data and Machine Learning.

Chartered Retirement Planning Counselor<sup>™</sup> (CRPC®)
College For Financial Planning - Austin, TX
Professional Designation

Bachelor of Arts, Psychology St. Joseph's College – Patchogue, NY